<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.rpdev.OpenTodoList</id>
  <name>OpenTodoList</name>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <summary>Todo list and note taking application</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <developer_name>Martin Höher</developer_name>
  <description>
    <p>
        OpenTodoList is a todo list and note taking application. It is
        available for Linux, macOS and Windows as well as on Android.
        Your information can be shared across devices to keep everything
        up date date, where ever you go.
    </p>
    <ul>
        <li>Organize todo lists, notes and other items in libraries</li>
        <li>Synchronize out-of-the-box with NextCloud, ownCloud and other WebDAV
            servers
        </li>
        <li>Use sync clients of your choice to synchronize with arbitrary
            services</li>
        <li>Schedule items by setting due dates on them</li>
        <li>Use Markdown in item titles and descriptions to format text
            as you like</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>
        Libraries can contain todo lists, notes and images
      </caption>
      <image>https://opentodolist.rpdev.net/images/appstream/library_page.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://opentodolist.rpdev.net/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://gitlab.com/rpdev/opentodolist/issues</url>
  <launchable type="destkop-id">net.rpdev.OpenTodoList.desktop</launchable>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
  <update_contact>martin_AT_rpdev.net</update_contact>

  <releases>
      <release version="3.25.0" date="2020-08-03">
        <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                #348: Update to Qt 5.15.
            </li>
            <li>
                #355: Also use syntax highlighting on macOS and iOS.
            </li>
            <li>
                #308: Notarize app on macOS.
            </li>
            <li>
                #333: Fix some random failures in CI testing.
            </li>
            <li>
                #181: Better text styling + code syntax highlighting when viewing text.
            </li>
            <li>
                #344: Update day ranges in schedule view more regularly.
            </li>
            <li>
                #347: Fix missing/extra separators between items in schedule view.
            </li>
        </ul>
      </release>
      <release version="3.24.0" date="2020-07-07">
        <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                #346: Make sure we pull all changes from the server.
            </li>
            <li>
                #350: Fix connections to some WebDAV servers (due to wrong Depth-header).
            </li>
            <li>
                #289: Use ccache in CIs.
            </li>
            <li>
                #295: Allow changing the font size used by the app.
            </li>
            <li>
                #345: Ensure buttons in side bar to collapse tags of a library are large enough.
            </li>
            <li>
                #349: Unify dots-menu and menu holding hidden tool bar actions.
            </li>
            <li>
                #153: Auto-scroll during drag and drop.
            </li>
            <li>
                #352: Remove due date controls from task related user interfaces.
            </li>
        </ul>
      </release>
      <release version="3.23.0" date="2020-06-01">
        <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                #337: Allow to quickly add new items on the scheduling page.
            </li>
            <li>
                #292: Disable auto-backup on Android.
            </li>
            <li>
                #340 and 343: Highlight the today in the due date selection dialog.
            </li>
            <li>
                #342: More white-space in todo/task lists.
            </li>
            <li>
                #339: Deal with redirects of WebDAV servers (and implement special handling, as
                this seems to be required for some WebDAV backends).
            </li>
            <li>
                #338: Allow to quickly re-schedule items on the schedule page.
            </li>
            <li>
                #332: Implement recurring items.
            </li>
            <li>
                #334: Fix a crash when using the search function.
            </li>
            <li>
                #330: Fix a unit test that sporadically failed.
            </li>
            <li>
                #329: It is possible again to add tags to todo lists.
            </li>
            <li>
                #331: Fix the git submodule URLs used (they need to be absolute in our case).
            </li>
        </ul>
      </release>
      <release version="3.22.0" date="2020-05-01">
        <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                #320: Allow to collapse/expand libraries in the side bar.
            </li>
            <li>
                #324: Retain QML files in the app (so it continues to work even if the used Qt
                version is updated without recompiling the app).
            </li>
            <li>
                #315: Update to Qt 5.14.2 for most target platforms.
            </li>
            <li>
                #322: Also use new icon on iOS.
            </li>
            <li>
                #323, #316: Do not show HTML code in the popup indicating that a new item has been
                created.
            </li>
            <li>
                #170: The code is now checked by some static code checkers.
            </li>
        </ul>
      </release>
    <release version="3.21.1" date="2020-04-10">
      <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
      <ul>
          <li>
              #313: Fix the Launcher Icon an Android.
          </li>
          <li>
              #314: Fix a potential crash during start up, when the user had library created in
              old releases.
          </li>
      </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.20.0" date="2020-03-02">
      <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
      <ul>
          <li>
              #197: It is now possible to add additional pages of text to a note (hence, making
              notes a kind of notebook instead).
          </li>
      </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.19.1" date="2020-02-17">
      <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
      <ul>
          <li>
              #295: Due dates of items creates in some time zones are no longer shown one day off.
          </li>
          <li>
              #296: Fix an issue which causes the app to not start anymore on Windows.
          </li>
          <li>
              #294: When a library is currently synchronized, an indication is shown in the tool bar (instead of a custom overlay footer), which would cover the content and prevent users from interacting.
          </li>
      </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.19.0" date="2020-02-12">
      <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
      <ul>
          <li>
              #285: The app now has "accounts", which makes handling of multiple
              libraries on the same server much easier.
          </li>
          <li>
              #283: Close swipe delegates in todo lists after toggling done state.
          </li>
          <li>
              #281: Double click todos/tasks to change their name.
          </li>
          <li>
              #286: Add link to the app's POEditor.com page in the side bar.
          </li>
          <li>
              #287: Improve about/license page.
          </li>
          <li>
              #288: Fix sync with LuckyCloud (and with this a lot more WebDAV servers).
          </li>
      </ul>
  </release>
    <release version="3.18.0" date="2020-01-04">
        <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                #280: Fixed an issue which caused the app to crash when
                terminating it on Android and iOS.
            </li>
            <li>
                #203: Fixed opening images from the Gallery on Android
                devices.
            </li>
            <li>
                #277: Properly install a *.desktop file, which is required
                for some systems like Flatpak to extract meta information.
            </li>
            <li>
                #256: The user experience using the Snap version of the app
                has been improved. Concrete, the snap contains all of the
                dependencies, so it is no longer required to run
                some cryptic "connect" commands manually after the installation.
            </li>
            <li>
                #261: Items in the library page can now be sorted (e.g.
                by name or due date).
            </li>
            <li>
                #271: When running on mobile devices or when the app window
                is rather small, dynamicall show tool bar icons and do not
                cut them off. Additionally, show a menu which contains all
                actions which are not currently shown as toolbar icons.
            </li>
            <li>
                #272: The app is now properly packaged and available via
                the iOS app store.
            </li>
            <li>
                #262: Store the created at and updated at timestamps. These
                properties can be used when sorting items e.g. in the library
                page or inside a todo list.
            </li>
            <li>
                #259: Fix the app translations. They now work again.
                Additionally, users can select the language to show the app
                in using the settings.
            </li>
            <li>
                #264: In todo and tasks lists, one can now use a swipe
                from left to right to mark the todo or task as done (or undone).
            </li>
            <li>
                #274: Improved the todo drawer. There were several usability
                issues with the previous implementation, such that it did not
                resize properly and it was not possible to use swipe gestures
                in it.
            </li>
            <li>
                #247: Added a button to set the due date in the swipe menu
                in todo lists to quickly add a date.
            </li>
            <li>
                #282: Generate proper version numbers for iOS release.
            </li>
            <li>
                #279: Ensure the app generates proper file names when adding
                images. This is especially important on iOS when adding
                images from the gallery.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.16.1" date="2019-10-03">
        <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                #255: Update Android release to Qt 5.13.1.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.16.0" date="2019-10-01">
        <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                #252: The KDE runtime used for the Flatpak build has been
                updated to v5.13.
            </li>
            <li>
                #253: The app now supports a dark theme. In the newly added
                settings page, the user can select the preferred theme for the
                Material style. One can select either the Light or Dark theme
                or opt to follow the system color palette.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.15.0" date="2019-09-08">
        <p>This release includes the following changes:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                #235: Todos inside a todo list can now be ordered by their
                title or due date. In addition, manual sorting is still
                possible as well.
            </li>
            <li>
                #246: It is now possible to set a due date when creating a new
                todo.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.13.0" date="2019-06-30">
        <p>
          This release includes the following changes:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            #223: The has been packages as a snap. This makes it
            super easy to install on Linux distributions including
            snap.
          </li>
          <li>
            #224: When running the app packages via Flatpak, passwords
            are now written to the secrets store (like Gnome keyring or
            the KDE Wallet). Before, they have been written to a less
            secure fallback location.
          </li>
          <li>
            #230: A bug has been fixed, which caused the app to crash when
            using the search. This bug did not occur all the time.
            In particular, it seemed to occur most often when the app
            was run as an AppImage.
          </li>
          <li>
            #237: The Schedule view has been extended and now includes
            a Tomorrow section, showing all the items which are due on the
            next day.
          </li>
          <li>
            #238: Background images have been removed from most views. They
            did not contribute to the usability of the app and even
            worse made the app unnecessarily hard to use for users
            who are sight impaired.
          </li>
          <li>
            #232: A bug has been fixed which caused the app to not
            allow the user to add images to a library when being run
            as an AppImage.
          </li>
          <li>
            #233: When being packages as Flatpak, the app now is able
            to display color emoji out of the box.
          </li>
          <li>
            #236: A bug has been fixed which caused items in the schedule
            view to appear in the wrong section under some circumstances.
          </li>
        </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.12.0" date="2019-06-09">
        <p>
            This release adds the following new features to the app:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>#228: Syntax highlighting in note editors</li>
        </ul>
        <p>
            In addition, the following changes have been done (where
            applicable):
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>#213: Update to Qt 5.12.</li>
            <li>#214: Better handling of the app cache.</li>
        </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.11.0" date="2019-03-03">
        <p>
            This release adds two new features to the app:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>#218: You can now re-order images inside a library</li>
            <li>#204: A manual progress value can be set on todos</li>
        </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.10.3" date="2019-02-27">
        <p>
            This is a bug fix release with patches some issues with the
            Flatpak version of the app.
        </p>
    </release>
    <release version="3.10.0" date="2019-01-27">
      <p>
        This release is rather a maintenance release. It upgrades to at least
        Qt 5.11 on all supported platforms, some even to Qt 5.12. The most interesting
        part is probably that the app is now available via Flatpak. Here is the list of
        all issues that went into the release:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>#209: Update to Qt 5.11.2</li>
        <li>#211: Build ready to be used APKs in the CI</li>
        <li>#215: Build the app as Flatpak</li>
        <li>#216: AppImage is no longer working</li>
        <li>#219: Improve AppData File</li>
        <li>#220: Desktop file needs icon specified</li>
      </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="3.9.0" date="2018-11-11">
        <p>
            This relase fixes the issues #208, #202, #90, #210, #207,
            #193 and #191. The most notable change among these is the
            introduction of an item cache, which speeds up several
            aspects of the app (start-up, listing of large item
            collections and so on).
        </p>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
